♪ In the
not-too-distant future ♪
♪ Somewhere in time and space ♪
♪ Mike Nelson and
his robot pals ♪
♪ Are caught in
an endless chase ♪
♪ Pursued by a woman
whose name is Pearl ♪
♪ An evil gal who wants
to rule the world ♪
♪ She threw a few
things in her purse ♪
♪ And in her rocket
ship she hunts them ♪
♪ All across the universe ♪
- I'll get you!
♪ I'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst I can find ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And I'll monitor his mind ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Mike can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ He'll try to keep his sanity ♪
♪ With the help of
his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call ♪
♪ Cambot ♪
- You're on!
♪ Gypsy ♪
- Oh my stars!
♪ Tom Servo ♪
- Check me out!
♪ Croooow ♪
- I'm different!
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ Just repeat to yourself
it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000 ♪
(guitar twangs)
(mechanical rumbling)
(doors closing)
- Got it. All right
Gyps, take it away.
- [Gypsy] Okay, Mike.
- Hey, what happened
to Crow there?
- Oh, he went outside to
check the ship's gutters,
a derecho kicked up and he got
caught in a freak hailstorm.
- Sure is the
season for 'em, huh?
- Yeah, about three
grand in hail damage.
It's gonna be about
three weeks in the shop
but Gyps gave me
a loaner Crow, so.
- Cool.
It's that old AMC
Crow that Gypsy's
been tinkering with for years.
- Hey guys, are there
things that are happening?
- (coughs) He must
be running rich.
- Yeah well, I'll flip
his air filter cover over
and he should be fine.
- Check it out, he's
got a killer radio.
- Oh wow, cool.
(mellow music)
- We'll be right back.
- Later we'll take
stuff and do it, right?
- Shhh.
(instrumental theme music)
- Where does the continuing
of things which goes again?
- Man, he's getting worse.
- Heyooo!
- Hey, Crow you
look as good as new.
- Yeah, Gypsy covered me
with a layer of TruCoat.
Hey, fake me, she needs
you back at the shop.
Some other guy's Crow got
trashed by a semi on i-95.
- Other guy's Crow?
- To have set goodbye to things.
- All right, okay.
Oh, Pearl S. Buck is calling.
- Cheap model.
- Yeah.
- Okay Nelson, time for
your semiannual checkup.
So how are you
feeling these days?
- Doing very well these
days, Pearl, thank you.
- No physical pain
anywhere? No mental anguish?
No vague feelings of
unease, poor sleep,
crying jags, hives, corns?
- No.
Well, I was a bit
upset a few days ago
when I lost some shiny
bottlecaps that I quite liked,
but I found them, and ever
since it's been damn good times.
I'm feeling very, very happy
and I've never felt healthier.
I have a good life, thank you.
- Why!? What is wrong with you?
I work my fingers to the bone
trying to make you miserable
and you have the insensitivity
to tell me you're happy?
- You know Pearl,
it might behoove you
to reevaluate the
experiment itself.
As a wise old
observer once said,
to constantly repeat
the same action
and expect a variant reaction
is surely a sign of madness.
- Then why do you keep
mouthing off to me?
You get the same
reaction every time.
- Point taken.
- Okay Nelson, as a scientist
I must determine for myself
what is methodologically
incorrect about this setup.
I'm going in.
You and me are gonna
trade places for today.
Okay brainstem, do it.
- Gosh, sorry.
(popping)
- Whoa!
- Now remember Mike,
if you try to escape
while you're down here,
each of these two creeps
is willing, able, even
anxious to kill you
in many different horrible ways.
But for the sake of
scientific control,
I want you to relentlessly
browbeat them, just like I do.
And I will act real bland up
on the satellite just like you.
Going up, chalky.
(popping)
(Bobo chuckling)
- Hello, Mike.
- Mike.
- Mike!
(laughing)
- Mike.
- Well, it looks like
we got us a free ride!
Woohoo.
- Yeah.
No movie, no Mike. Cool!
- Par-tay!
(popping)
- Not so fast Tinkertoys,
we got some cinema to watch.
Hey Brain Guy, send up
"Quest of the Delta Knights."
That'll hurt me so bad.
(Pearl laughing)
(alarms blaring)
- Movie sign!
Pearl, that's movie sign,
meaning you'll kill you
if you don't hurry
into the theater!
- Ah, delightful!
I forget what a nice subtle
touch I have sometimes.
Good for me.
(mechanical rumbling)
(doors opening)
- [Tom] See, right off the bat
I got a problem with this movie.
- [Crow] Redge.
- [Narrator] From
the land comes life.
- [Pearl] And fat-free goodness.
- [Narrator] Many years ago,
terror stalked the land,
making life harsh,
unfair, and treacherous.
- [Crow] Jimmy
Carter was in office.
- [Narrator] The
principal agent of evil
was the wicked black
knight Lord Vultare.
Only one group dared defy him,
the sacred order of
the Delta Knights.
They alone possessed the secrets
that could destroy him.
Vultare obsessed with
discovering these secrets.
He attacked indiscriminately,
desperately searching
for clues that could lead
him to the Delta Knights.
it was a time of
darkness and danger,
the time of heroes and villains.
- [Tom] Yeah, and
Ren Fest rejects.
- [Narrator] For
the Delta Knight.
♪ Touch down in the land
of the Delta Knights ♪
- [Pearl] Witchiepoo
cracks down on Pufnstuf.
- [Tom] Take care
of my leather mug!
insult people from the suburbs!
- [Pearl] Oh, Joan Blondell.
- [Tom] Yo!
Packers!
- [Crow] My boat.
- [Pearl] Ah geez, I
forgot my cigarettes.
I'm gonna have a mint,
you guys want a mint?
(bots agreeing enthusiastically)
That's the last one I got, you
can clean it off if you want.
- [Tom] Okay, thanks.
- [Pearl] Here, I'll
split it for ya.
- [Crow] Thanks, Pearl!
- [Tom] Thank you Pearl.
(bots chewing loudly)
- [Crow] Well, better than
"Quest of the Delta
Burkes," I suppose.
- [Tom] Gregg Allman
for sale here!
- 75, who'll give me 75?
- [Pearl] Dagnabbit, Lukey.
- [Crow] This
sounds like a movie
that should have
Matthew Broderick in it.
- [Tom] Yeah, when these
guys aren't writing
lines of code, they're
out doing this crap.
- [Pearl] Ah, the lead
singer for Canned Heat.
- Leave him alone.
(auctioneer calling)
- [Crow] Ashley Wilkes
is coming a-callin'.
- [Woman] Get off him.
What kind of man
strikes a child?
- [Tom] Me sorry.
- [Pearl] Hi, I'm Simply Red.
- [Crow] 20th century'll
be here any day now.
You'll be fine.
- [Man] Get away from him!
- [Tom] hey programs,
getcha programs here.
- [Pearl] Is that a beard
or a toilet seat cover?
- [Crow] In it for
the money, folks.
- [Auctioneer] This one, Lot 47.
- [Tom] He stuck his
face in dryer lint.
- [Pearl] Hey geek.
- [Tom] Hey wizard.
(indistinct)
- [Crow] Beef tink and
chicken blonk and pork flunk.
- Any other bids?
Lot 47, sold for 75.
Look at this.
Lot 37.
- [Pearl] Comes with
a free pool cue.
- A fine young lad.
Who'll give me five?
(crowd shouting)
You'll find lots
of uses for him.
(shouting and jeering)
- [Crow] He takes lance
wounds in the chest well
as you can see.
- Three pieces, who'll
get us going at three?
- For that crippled imbecile?
- [Tom] Good one,
breast-exposing lady.
- One, come now, one silver,
he's worth ten times that.
- [Woman] Then you buy him.
- [Crow] "Then you buy
him." You hear that?
"Then you buy him."
What a stitch.
- Now come, every
lot must be sold.
Who'll give me one?
- One.
- -[Pearl] Stick.
- Ah, one silver. Do I hear two?
Two silver pieces?
- Copper.
(indistinct)
One copper.
- [Tom] Who goosed me?
- You're mad. That's an insult!
You get out of here, you swine,
or I'll have you flogged!
- [Woman] Let's see the girl!
- [Woman] Bring on the girl.
- Move along!
- Milady, I can't
accept a copper.
- Take it and move along,
or would you prefer
I spoke to my cousin,
the Lord Vultare?
- Sold.
- [Pearl] The movie
titles continue
til the very end of the movie.
- [Crow] Next up,
Pippi Longstocking.
- [Tom] I'm so happy.
- [Pearl] Stupid shirt,
I'm gonna hurt you man.
Stupid dumb shirt.
- [Crow] Here now,
have some angel dust.
- What's your name, boy?
- [Tom] Jonathan
Taylor Thomas, I think.
- [Pearl] His underwear and
his hat are interchangeable.
- Como te llamas?
- [Tom] Yeah, yo quiero
Taco Bell, whatever.
- Comment vous-appelez vous?
- [Crow] Je m'appelle bite me.
- [Pearl] I'm actually just
apartment-sitting
for my brother.
- [Tom] Welcome. I like to
call it the plague nest.
- Wie heisst du?
(Crow makes random
babbling noises)
- [Pearl] He's the
lost member of ZZ Top.
- So, you have no name.
- [Tom] if I lit
your head on fire,
would that jog your memory?
- Time for food.
- [Crow] Hope you like rats.
- English, eh?
my name is Baydool.
- [Tom] Oh no, wait, that's
my intestinal condition.
- Can you say Baydool?
- [Pearl] Let me try.
Get bent. No, I guess I can't.
- You're no longer
a slave, understand?
- [Crow] You're the
hostage of a madman.
- This is your home now.
- [Pearl] You'll
live in this basket.
- You have a roof
over your head.
Keeps out the rain,
most of the time anyway.
There's always
food on the table.
- [Crow] And food in my beard.
- Would you like some food?
- [Tom] I would but what's
that crap you're holding up?
- All you have to do is ask.
- [Pearl] And so help
me, I'll put you down.
- [Tom] Ah, it's Martin Landau.
- it's a disguise.
There are times when
you need a disguise.
Disguises come in
handy now and then.
- [Crow] like when you're
cruising Sunset Boulevard.
- [Baydool] Don't be afraid.
- [Pearl] I'll see if
Bombadil has a place to crash.
- [Tom] No, it's
Joe Walsh! Aaah!
(instrumental theme music)
- [Crow] Robert Bork
takes a constitutional.
- [Pearl] He's a living
Dr. Seuss character.
- [Tom] Oh please, no, no!
- [Crow] What's he
pulling out!? Help!
- [Pearl] Eww, wizard whiz.
- [Crow] He drained the wizard.
(disgusted exclamations)
- I beg your pardon, sir.
(indistinct)
Come inside boy, there's
all sorts of rubbish
in the streets at this hour.
- [Tom] That's my pee!
- [Crow] The pee throwing
scene. ladies and gentlemen.
- [Pearl] Now I'm
going to attach
Rosey Grier's head
to your shoulder.
- [Tom] You're funny.
I like you.
- You bet I am.
- [Crow] You gave us a mint.
- Yeah.
- Excuse me?
- My name is Travis.
- [Crow] Man, do
you ever shut up?
- Travis.
(cracking)
- [Pearl] Oh, sorry.
- That's a fine name.
- [Tom] If you're gay.
- How is it you came
to be sold as a slave?
- [Crow] I accidentally
put a sign on myself
that read "slave for sale."
- A big battle was coming.
My father sent us to safety.
- [Pearl] He wasn't
very good at that.
- They attacked.
- It's all right now, Travis.
All is well.
- [Tom] Oh yeah I got bought
by a beard-wearing psycho,
had half a can of
pee thrown at me,
yeah, things are great.
- Call me Tee.
- [Crow] Huh,
kid's kind of dumb.
- [Pearl] And during the day
I'm a Stevie Nicks impersonator.
- [Tom] No, Gaul is
that way, damn it.
- [Crow] Pots, pots for
throwing pee at your neighbors.
- [Pearl] Good news,
only 20% of the village
died of the plague overnight.
- [Tom] Can someone
spare some coffee?
- [Crow] A latte, anyone?
I'll even take decaf.
- [Pearl] Here you are,
toenail clipping then.
- [Tom] Back now, this
is a lot of money.
- [Crow] Hey, a wheat penny.
- [Pearl] I got some
lint and a bloody molar.
- [Tom] Hurry up, I gotta
fly a Sopwith Camel in a minute.
- [Crow] Halt, Sir
Dan of Blocker.
♪ Master Bojangles, beg ♪
- [Tom] That's great, Pearl.
Ah, my pyramid begging
scheme is working.
- [Crow] Watch, I'm gonna
kill all the ants, watch.
- [Tom] Bring in da
noise, bring in da funk.
- [Pearl] I think the funk
is pretty well covered
by these folks.
- [Crow] We make
less when you dance.
- [Tom] I could buy
and sell your ass.
- [Pearl] Oh, the
medieval Deney Terrio.
- [Crow] Cat heads for the rats.
- Food!
I'll be right back.
- [Tom] We heard about
the kid who dances.
We're from the
William Morris Agency.
(villagers yelling)_
- [Pearl] Alan Hale!
- [Man] At your
service, Lord Vultare.
- [Vultare] Shut up and get
these criminals to the brig.
Now, let the fate
of these wretches
serve as a lesson to you all!
Insurrection will
not be tolerated
in the land of the Mannerjay.
- Murderer!
- [Tom] Aw, they killed
her personal Smurf.
- Murderer!
- [Pearl] He was
a great peasant!
- What is that?
- Lord Vultare.
- [Tom] last week on "Knights."
- He's the one.
- The one, Tee?
- [Crow] Safe!
♪ Oooooklahoma where the wind ♪
- He killed my mother.
- [Vultare] Oh,
stop that. Stop it.
Guard, have these
people dispersed
or I'll arrest them as spies!
- [Pearl] He's
reading "Ye Firm,"
- Who's Cato?
- [Crow] Clouseau's house boy.
- You can read. Tee,
that's magnificent.
Where did you learn?
- [Tom] Hooked on Phonics.
- Don't be afraid, you can read.
it's wonderful.
- [Pearl] Read me
"Portnoy's Complaint."
- Who taught you?
- No one.
- You taught yourself?
- [Crow] Well, I can
only read the word Cato.
- From lands far to the
north will come a young sage.
- [Tom] Oh, Garrison Keillor.
- Pardon me?
- This is an atlas,
there are maps in it.
- [Pearl] Uh yeah, that
would be an atlas, yes.
- England.
- [Crow] Dan & John Ford Coley.
- You can read maps as well?
- Our manor house was
just outside London.
- Your manor house, really?
- [Tom] He's trying to
get himself invited.
- No, not master, Tee.
You're free now, you're no
longer a slave, remember.
- My mother taught me
those whom we respect,
those with great wisdom and
dignity, we should call master.
- [Crow] Right Mr. Bater?
- I can live with that.
- [Tom] I can also
live with my scabies.
- [Pearl] Aah, another
plague-ridden day.
- [Crow] Rubber Soul font.
What the?
Please hammer, don't hurt him.
- Go on, go on. You
know what I want.
Fix it and bring it
back before nightfall.
- [Pearl] Hey how's
it going Pete?
- [Crow] Not bad, Charlie.
- Well, what is it?
Don't stand there
flapping your jaws.
Have I responded to
the Emperor of Cathay?
- Yes, your ladyship,
- What did I say?
- You refused him,
your ladyship, again.
- Of course I did, he's
dull and diminutive.
- [Tom] Danny DeVito?
- What else?
- As your ladyship ordered,
Lord Vultare is waiting.
- How long has he been waiting?
- Since midday, your ladyship.
- [Pearl] She's a Merv
Griffin production.
- It will have to do, I suppose.
Send him in.
♪ A time for us to
be in a crappy film ♪
- Doesn't she know who
she's meddling with?
- [Man] Well, evidently
not, your grace.
- The Panther of the Pyrenees.
The Scourge of Iberia.
- [Crow] The Sultan of Swing.
- I am forever your humble
servant, your loveliness.
- [Crow] Hi.
- Her ladyship will see you now.
- [Pearl] I gotta get back
to the New Power Generation.
- [Tom] Do you want me
to oscillate, ma'am?
- [Pearl] Never ask
Bootsy Collins if you
can borrow a coat,
- Yes?
- we've rounded up a
number of suspects.
- [Crow] Including Kevin Spacey.
- I'm certain some of them
are spies for the order.
- What of the map?
- No word. It seems...
- [Pearl] Chilly in here,
could you turn down your guy?
- Yes?
- It seems they're waiting.
- Waiting?
- [Crow] Beat it, wavey.
- Why would the
order be waiting?
- Well, maybe they're
waiting for the map
to arrive from
some far-off land,
or maybe they're waiting for
some person, I'm not sure.
- Not sure? Are you
trying, Vultare?
- Yes, your graciousness.
- Well try harder.
I can't have spies
hiding under every rock.
I just can't have it,
do you understand?
- it'll be done,
your loveliness.
- [Pearl] The hibachis
are going, sir,
if you want to stick
around for burgers.
(indistinct)
- [Tom] You ordered
decaf, right ma'am?
Pearl, carry me, okay?
- [Crow] Are they in an
underground parking garage?
Carry me too, Pearl.
- Come on.
(mechanical rumbling)
(doors closing)
- We love you, Pearl.
You are beautiful.
- You are beautiful
and you are wonderful
and we love you.
- Uh-huh, fine, whatever.
- You gave us a mint!
- Will you stay with us
forever and ever and ever?
- Nope.
Hey, Nelson.
(all laughing)
- Well, I'm out.
- Yeah, I got nothing here.
You cheatin' again, Brain Guy?
- Course I am!
(all laughing)
- I gotta tell you,
guys, this is great.
Just sitting around
with a couple of men
doing a little male bonding.
You are male aren't
you, Brain Guy?
- Last time I
checked, buddy boy.
Hey, ask your girlfriend,
she'll tell you I am.
(all laughing)
- No no, it's great though.
You know, to be sitting here
with a couple of man-sized men.
To not have to always be
the big clumsy
lummox all the time.
Down here that's you, Bobo.
(laughing)
- Well ask your girlfriend
she'll tell you I am.
- That doesn't
quite work, does it?
- Hey, whip us up another bottle
of single-malt there, will ya?
- Can do, Mikester.
(popping)
- I'm sorry we terrorized you
and tried to kill
you earlier, Mike.
- Ah, stuff it,
you big hairball.
I mean come on, kill
me? Who hasn't tried?
- Yeah, that's true.
- Wow, it's just
great to be away from
that lawgiver for a while.
You know he could be such a-
- Whoa, tell me about it.
Man, you know, someday
she's gonna tell me
to do something, I'm
just gonna look her
right in the eyes and I'll-
- [Pearl] Nelson!
(muttering)
- Hide the hooch.
- I'll rain horrible
fiery death on you later
for those remarks.
- Ha ha.
- Right now, I have the
conclusions of my evaluation
and I need a break from
these two chattering objects.
Okay Brain Butt, do it.
- No, you can't go, Pearl!
- Please don't leave us,
please, mint giver, we love you.
(popping)
- Whoa.
- Weird.
- Yuck! Weird.
- Hi guys, you miss me?
- Eh, I'm gonna
go take a shower.
Whoof, man.
- Oh yeah well, ask
your girlfriend,
she'll tell you that I...
(instrumental theme music)
- [Tom] Thank you. I guess.
- [Mike] Sure.
- Master, what's this?
- Hmm?
- [Tom] Damn, now I have to
tell him about the bodies.
- Perhaps it's time.
- [Mike] For you to shut
up and let me sleep.
- [Tom] I've invented a
device called the basement.
- [Crow] Nice new Birkenstocks.
- [Mike] Come on up, Mom.
- [Tom] Hope you like
watermelon rind pickles.
- [Crow] It's his
museum of odors.
- [Mike] So the big
secret is he's got
an unfinished basement
with water damage?
- Such wealth.
- [Tom] Is not in this box.
- Master...
Why do we beg?
- It allows me to
move around freely.
- [Crow] Like a good
pair of underwear.
- Master, you're a spy.
- [Mike] You're drawn
by Sergio Aragones.
- What do you know about spies?
- very little
- [Tom] Okay then, what
do you know about gelatin?
- I'm a member of the order.
- [Crow] He bats eighth.
- The Delta Knights.
The order is a secret
society dedicated
to bringing mankind
out of the dark ages
into an age of enlightenment.
- [Mike] We want
to open the door to
neutron bombs
infotainment and snacks.
- I suppose you
could say I'm a spy.
- [Tom] I'm semi-retired now,
don't do as much
spying as I used to.
- Delta Knights try
to achieve wisdom
by acquiring knowledge,
judgment, compassion,
- [Crow] Pee throwing skills.
- I've been waiting in
this town for five years.
- [Mike] Working at the A&W.
- Waiting for you.
- For me? Why?
- [Tom] I need you
to help me look for
the guy who's really
gonna help us.
- [Crow] I invented
staples, by the way.
- The prophecies.
From lands far to the north
will come a young sage.
- [Mike] Or you.
- Walking slow
and seeing little.
His special sight
will open the cage.
- [Tom] Bunch of crap, really.
- Your coming has been foretold.
You're from England.
- [Crow] Which is
unfortunate, but...
- You taught yourself to
read at the age of three.
when I first saw you
you could hardly walk.
Your one eye was swollen shut.
It's quite a fair
description, I would say.
- [Mike] You forgot
"love machine."
- What's the cage?
- The order has learned
that the lost storehouse
of Archimedes is located
somewhere here in this region.
- [Crow] You know,
somewhere around Europe.
- Archimedes?
- The greatest scientist
who ever lived.
It is thought that he had access
to the science of Atlantis.
- The lost continent.
- The most advanced civilization
mankind has ever known.
The surviving
secrets of Atlantis
were stored in the
library of Archimedes.
- [Tom] Mom!
- [Baydool] In 12 BC
the Romans attacked.
- [Mike] And pushed
down all our cheap sets.
- [Baydool] As the
battle raged on outside,
Archimedes struggled to preserve
these secrets and knowledge.
- [Tom] Let's get
that order up, people!
- [Baydool] chose this red
book, entitled "The Right Way."
- Show them the Corgon crystals.
- [Baydool] It was
fabled that Archimedes
was developing a new
weapon the Corgon crystals.
(indistinct)
- [Crow] Rocky!
- Go, go, go!
- [Baydool] As his apprentices
gathered the inventions
and hurried them to
safety, Archimedes raced
to finish the prophecies.
- [Mike] it's Sadie Hawkins Day!
- Where is Archimedes?
- Eureka!
- Bring him, now.
- One moment, I'm
almost finished!
- Surrender, old goat.
- [Mike] Oh, right
in the tomato.
- [Baydool] In his ignorance,
an nameless centurion
killed the greatest
scientist of all time.
- Leave him. He's nothing.
- - [Crow] Cock-a-doodle-doo.
- [Baydool] It was only
by the grace of God
that the red book survived.
Passed down through the
ages, this book is our key.
(eerie whistling)
- [Tom] Tea's ready!
- Just think what we could do
if we found the lost storehouse.
The magnificent
machines and knowledge.
Nothing less than a
blueprint for the future,
and you are the key
to take us there,
- [Tom] Well, you
and this other guy.
- When your training
is complete,
the order will send us the map.
- [Crow] I have hockey practice.
- I've already taught
you many things, Tee.
- [Tom] Has even a word
of this gotten through?
- But there are still
many things to learn.
- [Mike] We still haven't
cracked soap, for example.
- [Tom] Hey, hands off
the threads, creep.
- [Crow] Skip to
page 37 where Sonny
and the bridesmaid
are, well, you'll see.
- [Mike] Idiot, why did
I tell him I could read?
Hello?
- [Crow] And
Collinsworth grabs it,
will you look at him go!
- [Tom] Years later, he's
still on the first page.
- [Mike] Kid's turned
into Nellie Oleson.
- Now, these can put a person
to steep in no time at all.
- [Crow] They are tiny
James Michener books.
- [Crow] Hey!
- [Mike] Now here's
the dead man's brains
and here's his eyeballs.
- [Crow] Got a new humidor.
- [Tom] I have a wife
and family! Aaah.
- [Mike] NRA homeschooling.
(instrumental theme music)
Hi, townspeople,
it's not the beggar.
It's me, a nobleman.
- The time has come
but the map's not here.
Lord Vultare has intercepted it.
Look for the moor with
a patch over his eye
by the bakery, he will tell
us where to find the map.
- [Tom] You mean the dumpy nun?
- It'll be a nice
day if doesn't rain.
- It's always a nice
day if it doesn't rain.
- If the sun isn't too warm.
- [Mike] So you're a
Delta Knight too, huh?
- [Crow] He's really
rather an artless dodger.
- [Mike] A potato-chip, why?
(Tom quietly singing)
- [Tee] Is it a code?
- [Crow] I don't know, maybe.
I'm just farting around here.
- Recover map from
wizard Wamthool.
who's wizard Wamthool?
- [Mike] Ah, he's just a guy
I went to wizard school with.
- The Mannerjay's Merlin.
- [Tom] Yes, did a baby
Savior just get born here?
- [Mike] Oh, someone's
not overdressed.
- Yes?
- We were sent for.
- What?
- [Crow] Are we
in the same movie?
- You were?
(indistinct)
- Yes, I'm Dr.
Ramsian De Bourgeois,
and this is my
apprentice, Guy Alapatie.
- [Tom] Why don't you
have a seat in the bar
until we have a table for you?
- The call for magi?
- Magi?
- Oh yes, to decipher
some important paper.
- Oh right, of course.
Vultare's project.
- What a wonderful
laboratory you have here.
- Well, thank you.
- [Mike] He's got
a personal airbag.
- Is that the new Rasmic?
- Yes it is, I got
it just last month.
- [Tom] Man, am I foul today.
- Oh please help yourself.
- [Crow] He's an Erykah
Badu impersonator.
- I had another
one for many years.
It never worked but
this one I got on sale.
And look at the lens, I mean-
- [Mike] Hey, an ancient Servo!
- [Tom] Cool!
Ooh, that spittoon's
only for sharpshooters.
- [Mike] History's
first pepper grinder.
- Oh, Lord Vultare.
- What's going on?
- Excuse me?
- Any new progress with the...
- The map? Oh, I haven't
even begun that yet.
Well, I was waiting for
the experts to arrive.
- [Tom] Yes, did my,
um, test come back?
- Who are these people?
- The experts.
- I am Dr. Ramsian De Bourgeois,
and this is my apprentice.
- [Crow] Uh, fromage.
- Don't I know you?
- [Mike] Aren't you
me in another role?
- What's your name?
- Guy-
- I asked the boy.
- Guy...
- [Crow] Lafleur.
- Alapatie.
- We just arrived in your
fair city last night, milord.
- What are you doing here?
- We're magi.
- You asked for
experts, didn't you?
- [Tom] Can you believe I
gotta act with this guy?
- Let me see your papers.
You check their papers?
- I, no, no, okay
no. Everything-
- Have you filed your papers
with the chief scribe?
You imbecile, you
know the rules.
They should file first, how
can you operate without rules?
I find this totally
unacceptable!
- Unacceptable,
yes, but to a point.
Yes, yes.
I never got a memo,
never got a memo.
Ow ow, ow.
- Moron!
- I'm sorry, that's my
fault. My fault entirely.
[Crow] Hey, that's
also David Warner!
- [Tom] Yeah, Crow.
- [Mike] Sounds like
my bacon's ready,
I better go check that.
- [Tom] Do we have a
punchline written yet or...
- Are you sure you
copied everything down?
- Yes, every mark,
- [Crow] Maybe it's
your stupid brotherhood
that's the problem.
- There's no
indication of north,
there's no way to
orient the map.
- There must be.
What's this say?
- [Mike] "Children's
menu available."
- The arrow must show
where the father did glow.
- [Crow] E-I-E-I-O.
- Father is capitalized.
- Does that mean God the Father?
- [Tom] Or Steve the Father?
- Where did he glow?
- [Crow] At happy
hour every day,
- In the Holy Land?
- This map has been
waiting for you.
Only you.
- [Mike] Sorry I spilled
grape juice on it.
- Maybe it's your father.
- [Tom] Luke.
- [Baydool] Now
when did he glow?
- [Crow] Well, he did
drink a lot of phosphorous.
- With pride at your birth.
When you point the arrows
to the place of your birth,
we orient the map.
- [Mike] Now let's tap
that spigot on your head
and have some cider,
- Arrows toward England.
- Hmm.
- [Crow] Hmm, hmm
hmm. You're fired.
- Our years together have
been happy and full, Tee.
- Is he gonna ask me
to marry him? Oh no.
- But the time is near for
you to fulfill your destiny.
- [Mike] You shall be
a Maude impersonator.
- I'll not leave you, master.
- Don't deny me my destiny, Tee.
You will leave if you must.
- [Tom] Oh, and you
owe me back rent.
- Go to sleep now.
Tomorrow you have a very
important message to deliver.
- [Crow] Stupid destiny.
Dumb stupid destiny and stuff.
- [Tom] Is this my destiny?
- [Mike] Further. Keep going.
- [Crow] Wow, that was a
mistake that lasted six years.
- [Baydool] Godspeed, Travis.
- [Tom] And to your muffiny hat.
- [Crow] Introducing
plus-sized peasant wear.
- Baydool the beggar, come
out and show yourself!
- [Mike] Drop your pee and
come out with your hands up!
- [Tom] Look at
that, little buddy.
- [Crow] David Warner,
you are under arrest
by order of David Warner.
- Baydool the beggar,
I, Lord Vultare,
keeper of the law
for all the land,
charge you with crimes
against the Mannerjay
and of conspiring
with the order!
- [Mike] Can you
hear me over there?
(thunder crashes)
- [Tom] Later in
Castle Forrester.
- How's it coming, oh great one?
- [Crow] You ever
get back to Edmonton?
- I think I've got it.
Come here, come here.
I think I have it.
I think I've got it.
let me see.
- [Mike] Yes, I got the
role-on "Mad About You."
- No, no, no, that's not it.
No, haven't got it.
- [Tom] My Mongolian
barbecue is ready though.
- Maps. Why does he leave
me maps to decipher?
I'm no good with maps.
I get lost going to the moat.
- [Crow] why do they
call them moats anyway?
- [Mike] Medieval,
yes, but famous
for their brick oven pizzas.
- [Tom] Kind of
boring out tonight.
- [Crow] Cock-a-doodle-doo.
- [Mike] Hello, wall.
- [Tom] Hello.
- [Mike] Zero to
three in 12 seconds.
- It'll be a nice day
if it doesn't rain.
- It's always a nice
day if it doesn't rain.
- If...
- [Crow] She looks roughly
like Brian Dennehy.
- If the sun isn't too warm.
- [Crow] Gone.
- [Tom] It's a recipe
for slimy gruel.
- [Mike] Lots of bacteria,
you'll want to burn those off.
- [Baydool Voiceover] Danger,
go Maydeed's tavern for help.
Find storehouse now.
(instrumental theme music)
- Hello my friends, today on
Satellite of Love
Sunday Morning,
we are livid with
proudness in presenting
the Sir Thomas Neville Servo
Consort of the Middle Ages
Just After the Plague Singers.
They will favor us
today with an ancient
Aire on the Delta
Knights, in a new setting
by Sir Thomas Neville
Servo himself.
Let's enjoy.
♪ I sing of the
glorious Delta Knights ♪
♪ They live in
Europe somewhere ♪
♪ With Archimedes they
eat their Wheaties ♪
♪ And look pretty
good in fake hair ♪
♪ They're kind of afraid
to go out at night ♪
♪ They don't get historical
facts just right ♪
♪ They hike up their
codpieces really tight ♪
♪ They look pretty
good in fake hair ♪
♪ A sweet Delta
Lady am I, am I ♪
♪ More fair than the
stars in the sky ♪
♪ I'm bold and bawdy,
and oh, my Lawdy ♪
♪ I'm proud to declare ♪
♪ A sweet Delta Lady,
I do what I please ♪
♪ I'm strong and I'm
savvy and I've got these ♪
♪ I love to sing out,
"Don't forget the cheese" ♪
♪ I'm proud to
declare I like pie ♪
- Ah, fantastic, fantastic.
I know I won't soon
forget the cheese.
let us thank the Sir
Thomas Neville Servo-
- Oi mate, let's
have a dirty one!
- Right!
- No, no, no, no-
♪ Oh, I love to mush me buckles
in me missus' pigeon pie ♪
- Please, no, please.
Sir Thomas, no.
I warned you about this song.
Out of my studio, I
want all of you out.
We have movie sign.
(alarms blaring)
Good day my friends.
(Servos singing)
(mechanical rumbling)
(doors opening)
- [Mike] Where did those
other Servos come from?
- [Tom] Eh, you know, around.
His codpiece is
made of actual cod.
- [Crow] the movie
next door is so loud,
that's really annoying.
- [Tom] Man, I need a cigarette.
(men arguing)
[Mike] You varmint!
- [Tom] Oh good, the
bars are still open.
(Tom chuckling)
(Mike groaning)
- [Crow] He looks
like Hayley Mills.
Which I don't mind, by the way.
- [Tom] If he runs into
a Klingon, I'm quitting.
- [Mike] What, he spits
mosquitoes through a straw
and they bite the victims?
- Hey, what was that?
- [Tom] Instant heart attack.
- [Crow] Yep, that's
what you gotta do
to get a table at this place.
- [Mike] Alanis
Morissette is in prison.
- [Tom] Finally.
- Here ya lads,
you're drinking again.
Drunk again. What's that?
- [Crow] My contact lens.
- Did you not get my message
telling you to go
to Maydeed's tavern?
- Yes.
- Then why are you here?
You should not have come.
- I had to.
- [Tom] They're
paying me to flog you.
(door creaking)
- What the devil's this?
- [Mike] Is that a
soccer ball on the table?
(all singing "Sledgehammer"
by Peter Gabriel)
- [Crow] So you wanna free
Mumia while we're here?
- [Mike] Yeah, I pretty much got
this medieval thing figured out.
♪ Born free ♪
- [Crow] Snipes,
Willis, Stallone.
Your table is ready.
Little scrawny blood kid, get
in and do their action scene.
- [Mike] This kid should really
wear a hairnet while fighting.
- Stop that right now!
(guards yelling indistinctly)
- Master!
- [Tom] They're
deploying bottle rockets!
(guards yelling)
- [Mike] Sultans,
pirates, after them!
- Call out the guards!
- [Crow] We are the guards!
- [Tom] Come on, let's
go hop the freight train.
- [Mike] Oh, I've got
a massive groin pull.
- [Crow] Now he's Sam Elliott.
- Am I trailing blood?
- [Mike] Aah! Uh, no, no.
- Hide yourself.
- [Mike] I'm sick
of looking at you.
- Tee, hide yourself quickly.
- [Crow] You better
get out of the way,
I'm in a pee throwing mood.
- I grow weary of your
antics, beggar man.
- [Crow] He eats his body
weight in moths everyday.
- Kill him.
- [Mike] People
are always trying
to hang their coats on this guy.
- [Tom] Look at that
turkey in the straw.
- The boy must have
got away. Move on.
- [Mike] Sir, are we
Saxons or Vikings?
What are we? Let's
settle on that.
- [Crow] Get me,
I'm St. Sebastian.
- Father?
[Mike] Aren't you glad I
broke you out of prison?
- You must find the storehouse.
- [Tom] And
liquidate everything!
- Before Vultare.
- [Mike] You're not
gonna do it, are you?
- Maydeen's tavern,
you'll find help there.
- [Crow] And a
decent happy hour.
You know, good chicken wings.
- God be with you.
- [Mike] Yeah. Is that
gravy on your lip?
- My son.
- [Tom] Who looks
like my daughter.
- [Crow] Oh, ow, ooh, that's
right on an arrow, ow.
- [Tom] He's sporting a
kicky little ponytail.
[Crow] Wow, his chopped up torso
is easier to carry
than I thought.
(patrons talking loudly)
- Hi
- [Mike] Hey, how's everything
at this table? Great.
- [Tom] (imitates goat
bleating) Help me.
- We need you.
Look at you, you gorgeous beast.
- [All] Norm!
- [Tom] How ya doing, everybody?
- [Crow] Sit outside
and pet our millipedes.
(Tom humming)
- [Mike] Wow, they had
Ethan Hawkes back then too?
- Come with me, boy. I'll show
you the time of your life.
- [Tom] We're going
to Camp Snoopy.
- Aren't you hungry?
- [Crow] Do you have
any Scurvy Meals?
- Yes?
- Don't I know you?
- [Mike] Didn't you seat me?
- Have I seen you before?
- You don't have to
be so clever here.
All you have to do is ask.
- [Tom] The first Hooters.
- [Crow] I'm too young for some.
- Is there anything you want?
Some dessert? Something
more to drink?
Something else?
- [Mike] 'Cause there's
a three dollar minimum.
- No.
- All right.
- [Tom] I'll take
these elsewhere.
- If you change your
mind, my name is Thena.
- [Crow] Yeah, yeah fine.
Look I'm probably gay so.
- [Mike] I call it Bluto.
- What are you doing?
- [Tom] Not getting
thrown up on, I hope.
- You're trying
to steal my soul!
- I was just drawing an image.
(men yelling)
- [Crow] Must smoke a Galois.
- [Mike] Ah, he's a little
woozy from not eating.
- [Tom] It's so awkward when
you're at the Ground Round
and you have to
kill another person.
- [Mike] Tell me about it.
- Thank you, friend.
I'm Leonardo.
Is this your first time
in Madam Maydeed's?
- Yes.
- And in Florence?
- [Mike] Wow.
(indistinct)
- A reader?
A man at to my own heart.
As a token of my gratitude,
can I buy you a drink?
- No, thanks.
- Can I get you
something to eat?
- [Crow] They have a Playland.
- Anything?
- [Tom] He studied at the
Royal Academy of Dan Cortese.
- The girl?
Here at Madam Maydeed's, you
can have anything you want
if you have the coin,
even a lovely bedwarmer.
- [Mike] Big guy's
sweat is good today.
- [Tom] He bought
his hat at Cinnabon.
- [Crow] He's staying
at a bed and Ren Fest.
- [Mike] I'm a
door-to-door Harlequin,
you need any
Harlequin-ing done here?
- Wake up.
- [Crow] It's time
to go to sleep.
(indistinct)
- [Tom] Eee, ooh, you,
ooh, eeh, ah, ooh. Andy.
- [Mike] He's trying to use
the remote control on him.
- [Crow] Look, there's
outdoors out there.
- [Tom] Vikings lost.
(lively music)
- [Mike] Oh, for
cryin' out loud.
Oh damn, the safety was on.
- [Tom] Good thing he's
not writing a Pinto,
it might explode.
(chuckling) Sorry.
- Thanks, for waking me.
- You're welcome.
Besides, Travis, you'd
do the same for me.
- Call me Tee.
- Tee?
- [Crow] it's short for R.
- So why did you
steal Vultare's horse?
- I figured he'd
have the best one.
- [Mike] But it
pulls to the left.
- Do you think we
should split up,
make it more difficult
for them to follow us?
- It depends on the weather.
- What do you mean?
- It'll be a nice day
if it doesn't rain.
- It's always a nice
day if it doesn't rain.
- If the sun isn't too warm.
- You're my contact?
- [Tom] Let me see
your tiny time pills.
- You're a Delta Knight?
- Looks that way.
I was born in a small
town called Vinci.
about 10 years ago, I
moved to Florence to study.
- My master is a
member of the order.
Oh no.
- You're not going anywhere
on that beast. Look.
Here, ride with me.
- [Mike] Hey, that's always
been there. I run just fine.
- Come on!
- Rather persistent,
aren't they?
[Crow] Leonardo barely
escaped being called
Leonardo da Gary, Indiana.
- [Tom] Yeah, then my
dad got transferred
and I was Leonardo da Oxnard
for a couple of years.
- This isn't about
horses, is it?
- Probably not.
- Are you going to tell me
or am I gonna have to
drag it out of you?
- [Mike] The horse is
wearing a modest skirt.
- We took something.
- What did you take?
- [Crow] A lot of
little sugar packets.
- The slave market.
- Slave market?
You took the slave market?
- I knew she looked familiar.
- Who?
- Thena. The serving girl.
The one Vultare just bought.
Turn around.
- What?
- Turn around
- [Crow] Bright eyes.
- I'm telling you right
now, I don't like this.
- [Mike] Hey, the
horse isn't wearing
any underpants under that skirt.
- [Tom] Medieval Gold,
24 madrigals by 24 stars!
- This way, men.
The last (indistinct)
must be just ahead.
I can't believe you idiots
let them steal my horse!
You'd better watch my face
more closely, Brandow.
- Very good, sir.
[Crow] they're working
as head hunters
for a rival tavern.
- [Thena] Let me go!
- And another thing, Brandow-
- [Mike] Yep, wench-jacking
was a big problem
during the Middle Ages.
- Stop, stop!
- It's you.
- Of course it is.
Who else would be such a fool
as to try and rescue you?
- Many real men would
give their lives for me.
- Why, when they could
have you for a few copper?
- If you think so little of
me, then why did you help me?
- I only helped because he-
- Stop it.
We don't have time for this.
Vultare and his men could
be here at any moment.
- Take the other horse,
I'll ride with you.
- Oh no you don't.
- We only have two horses.
- Doesn't matter, you're
not riding with me.
- Excuse me, little
miss princess.
- You're not riding with me!
- Enough!
I'll ride with you.
- [Tom] They're gonna
have to check each other
for ticks when they get home.
- Princess.
♪ Give us British Sterling ♪
- [Mike] How'd you
get a restraining
order on me so quick?
- [Tom] (sighing) Well,
huzzah, I suppose.
- [Crow] It's a Nicole
Kidman in the wild.
- You stole something, did you?
- [Mike] Hello? Hey,
mead-for-brains.
- what did you steal?
- [Tom] Pretzels.
- Money, jewels? A map to
the lost storehouse, perhaps?
- How did you know that?
- Oh, come on, Tee.
In addition to being
a pretty good artist
I'm great with maps
so how about it?
- [Mike] How great can
you really be at maps?
- [Crow] It's like being
good at eating cereal.
- Who drew this?
- [Mike] My grandma,
was born without arms.
- I copied it.
- Ah. A noble effort.
- [Tom] Yeah, for
using your butt.
- So. about the girl.
- What about her?
- Well, we can't very
well take her with us.
She'd slow us down.
- We can't just leave her here.
- We can give us some money,
she can take care of herself.
- She's coming.
- She's nothing but
a serving wench.
- That's not true.
- [Crow] She's a shift leader.
- The rules of the
order are very clear.
We're not just going
to abandon her.
- Watch this.
- [Mike] I'm gonna short
sheet her sleeping bag.
- [Tom] Can we see
the dessert tray?
- Come now, I think two
silvers is more than fair.
- I said no.
Doing something
when you are forced
and doing something
in your own free will
are two different things.
- How about three?
- I said no.
- Leave her alone!
- I'm no longer a slave.
- [Crow] Ah, I'm gonna
go design a helicopter.
(wolf howling)
- [Mike] Is that a block
and tackle for his crotch?
- [Crow] they pan over
and there's Balki.
(gasping)
(screaming)
- The Vikings in this
movie don't Vike very well.
- [Mike] Not at all.
(weapon firing)
- There's another one.
- Thena!
- [Tom] They must have
camped outside Sturgis.
- Vultare's scouts.
- I thought you
said we'd lost them.
- I don't know, maybe
they weren't scouts.
- [Mike] Well, I'm never
gonna get back to sleep now.
- They were scouts, all
right, but not very good ones.
If they'd killed us, Vultare
surely would have killed them.
- [Tom] And this guy
fell on our bread.
- Maybe they just
stumbled onto us.
- With the scouts dead,
Vultare will have to
decipher the map for himself.
- What?
- Nothing.
it's none of your concern.
- [Mike] Okay.
- We should get out of here.
- If it weren't for the girl,
they'd never have found us.
- I never asked for your help
- [Crow] Future
site of Euro Disney.
- [Tom] Well, the movie lost me.
It lost me and it's
trotting off without me.
- [Mike] "Bonanza,"
now in femme-y clothes.
- Sorry.
- [Crow] I was checking out
your cleavage from behind.
- For the way I treated you.
- [Tom] I like you.
(dopey laughing)
- Thank you.
- For what?
- Saving us back there.
- [Mike] And for your pillows.
- Why Leonardo, you
say the nicest things.
- [Crow] Yeah, that's how
they raise us in Vinci.
(instrumental theme music)
- [Tom] He needs new brake pads.
(shouting)
- [Crow] Are we being
attacked or entertained?
- [Tom] If only this was a
mask and not my face fungus.
- You're on our land.
- [Mike] Put on fruity
half-masks and be welcome.
- Come with us.
- [Crow] We're about to do
back rubs and
breathing exercises.
- [Tom] Mom bought me
this for trick and treat.
- Who are these people?
- I don't know, but
every moment that passes,
Vultare gets closer
to the storehouse.
- Don't let them lag behind.
- [Mike] And don't let
them loop their dialogue.
- [Crow] The tree's
infested with elves.
[Tom] And this winter
I'm planning on
being Leonardo da Cancun
for a couple of weeks.
- Are you all right?
- Who are these people?
- [Mike] Well, I'm Karl.
- I have no idea.
Do you?
- I'm not sure-
- Silence.
There'll be no talking by
Prince Jamteer's command.
- [Crow] Well, tell Prince
Jump-jugs we're sorry.
- Prince?
- [Mike] It's better
than being captured
by Morris Day, I guess.
- What are you doing?
- [Tom] Trying to
obey Prince Jump-jugs.
- When in doubt, rest.
- [Crow] You are full of
crap beyond your years, kid.
- [Mike] Hey, help!
- Open up.
Jamteer wants to see the girl.
[Tom] Well, if Jubja wants to
see the wirl, I guess we can.
- What's going on?
(indistinct)
- [Crow] Bent
Foliage State Prison.
- You leave her alone!
- I said back off, boy!
- Let me go!
- Thena!
- [Mike] Well, only 60
percent of their prisoners
break out the first night.
- Thena!
- [Tom] Can you bring
me a Klondike bar?
- [Crow] It's your
turn to meet Peter Pan.
- [Mike] This is about me not
pooling my tip money, right?
- Leave us.
- My liege.
- [Tom] My leech?
- Please, sit.
- Stay.
- [Tom] There's a midget
under her dress pushing up.
- [Crow] Lucky midget.
Midgets get everything.
- It's all right.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
- [Mike] Can I borrow
one of those things?
- Don't I know you?
- [Tom] Aren't you the
woman I just captured?
- [Prince] I think I've
seen you somewhere before.
- I doubt it, I've been
a slave since I was five.
- Since you were five...
- [Mike] That's a good
age to start as a slave.
- Tell me, what is your name?
- They call me Thena.
- [Crow] Fina, like
the gas station?
- Short for Athena?
Oh my god. My god, Athena!
- [Tom] Hey, I think
this is plot crap.
- Rando!
- Yes, my liege?
- [Prince] Sound the call, I
have great news for our people.
- As you wish.
(shouting)
- [Mike] Help me down!
- [Crow] Thanks for not
breaking the sticks.
- Come with us.
- What's going on?
- [Tom] Johnny Cash is
gonna entertain you tonight.
- Follow my lead.
- [Mike] Get hair extensions
and talk like a girl.
(villagers hooting)
- I'm going.
- [Crow] Gotta go visit
the howler monkeys.
- Now, Leonardo!
- [Tom] Oh, the plan is ruuuun!
- Where are you running to?
- What have you done
with these two now?
(high-pitched yelling)
- [Mike] Cheech Marin?
- Why did it have
to be (indistinct).
- They're over here!
- Follow me!
- Do I have a choice?
- [Tom] I'm starting
to like "Willow."
- I see them, I'm coming!
- [Crow] Oh, do you see them?
- Here, quietly.
- Quietly?
- [Mike] So the Ewoks grew
up to be big stupid men?
- I'm coming, I'm coming!
- Run, just run!
- [Crow] Unless I'm
mistaken, I'm fairly sure
that that one guy is coming!
- I'm coming!
(indistinct)
- Come on!
- [Mike] Snuggles the bear
is partying with his friends.
- There, there they are!
- Come on, Tee, hurry!
- [Crow] We're almost back to
where we first escaped from.
- [Tom] At least they're coming!
(laughing)
(halfhearted laughing)
- I'm coming!
- [Mike] Put a sock
in it, Legolas.
- I'm sorry for the way
you've been treated.
- You're sorry?
- What's going on?
- And I'd like to thank you
for bringing my sister
back to her people.
- Your sister?
- [Crow] Him or me?
- Perhaps I'd better let
Princess Athena explain.
- Princess Athena?
- [Crow] I'm coming!
- My god, Tee,
she is a princess.
- [Mike] Oh, her
dough has risen.
- Quite a change from a slattern
in a bawdy-house, isn't it?
Kidding.
- Athena was always a princess.
- [Crow] Or a cheerleader
or a naughty nurse.
- No matter what she had to do.
- [Tom] I just meant
she was a hooker.
- My two knights
in shining armor.
- Not so shining.
- [Mike] Does she have
a butt in her dress?
- You must be hungry.
I'll see that some
food is brought.
- [Crow] No whorin'
while I'm gone.
- Thank you.
- Prepare a feast, my
people, and rejoice.
Our princess has returned.
- You're really a princess?
- Yes, so Jamteer tells me.
This tree village serves as
my brother's hunting lodge.
After we eat, we have
to get some sleep
so we can leave at dawn.
- Leave at dawn?
- To get to the lost
storehouse before Vultare does.
- You know about
the lost storehouse?
- Yes, I heard you
talking to Tee about it.
- Have you told anyone?
- [Tom] Can we
got some crackers?
- No, no one.
- Please, Thena. I
mean, Princess Athena.
- You can still call me Thena.
- You can tell no one, Thena.
Please, you must promise.
- All right, I promise.
- You can't come with us.
- But you need help,
my brother and a few
of his most trusted men-
- No, Leonardo and
I have to go alone.
- [Tom] No.
- We belong to a secret society.
- The order.
- (scoffs) Just great.
- Yes.
As Delta Knights
we're sworn to do this
for the benefit of all mankind.
- [Mike] Except Dick Armey.
- I'm sorry, Thena.
- [Crow] I'm coming!
- [Tom] I'm coming!
(mechanical rumbling)
(doors closing)
- Come on, Gretzky.
♪ Cause I'm bad, shamon ♪
Ow, hey!
- Sorry, sorry.
- Hey hey, Mike, there's
some sort of a spaceship
approaching the port bow.
- Oh, Cambot, give me Rocket
Number Eleven Minus Two.
- Cute.
- Wow!
- Leonardo da Vinci!
Mr. da Vinci, it's
an honor to meet you.
- Hey, don't worry about
it, aight? Call me Leo.
And I call you?
- Oh, Mike and this
is Tom and Crow.
- Mike, Tom, Crow is it?
Crow? I like it,
Crow, it's good.
- Wow, Leo, I have to say I'm
amazed you're still alive.
- What, you been
talking to somebody?
What's so amazing
I'm still alive?
- I think he just
means, you know,
you were born such
a long time ago.
- What's a long time ago?
You know, I watch my
back, I stay alive.
- So you know, I have
so many questions
about your art, about your
incredible inventions.
- Or where the movie's
supposed to be taking place.
Everybody's English,
except maybe it's Greece.
you're what, Italian I assume?
What the heck is going on?
- Hey, it's a bad movie.
- Well, yeah but-
- Don't worry about it.
Anyway, the reason I come
by, I wanted to tell you
that this guy who's
playing me in the movie?
He's nothing like me.
He's a mook, he's a mama's
boy who should be home
with his mother and
his little sisters.
He's a mook, you know?
- Yeah, no, I agree, yeah.
- Hey, and I want to tell
you that I'm not a mook.
That's why I come by.
Should've called
first, I'm sorry.
- No, that's quite all right.
So you still livin' in Vinci?
- No, I came over in 1907.
I live in Queens now.
- Oh. What are you doing now?
You still inventing things or...
- Hey, I do what I
do. I'm in business.
Yeah, what do you do?
I mean Mike, who is this guy?
He's asking me questions,
he wants me to be dead.
- I didn't-
- What do you need
to know what I do?
Maybe I come over there
and show you what I do.
- Leo, no, Leo.
Come on, come on,
leave the kid alone.
Come on, he's all right.
- Okay Mike, I got
no beef with you.
But you talk to him.
- I will, I will, I will.
Hey Tom, listen up.
I don't want you to ever
ask Leonardo da Vinci
what he does for a living, okay?
- Okay. Whew.
(instrumental theme music)
- Goodbye.
- [Tom] What do I owe ya?
(chuckles) Just kidding.
- [Mike] hope that puberty
goes all right for you.
- God be with you, Tee.
- And with you, Princess.
- Come on, enough of that.
- [Crow] It's hard
to pick up chicks
when you look like Holly Hobbie.
[Tom] Poor horse
has had a bad night,
hanging in the trees.
- Farewell, safe journey.
- [Mike] Heil Hitler! Um...
- [Crow] Okay, let's
just lead him to water
and see what happens.
- [Tom] Hey, check it
out man, grass. Score!
- I don't see anything
that looks like
the entrance to anything.
- [Mike] Except your fly's open.
- Are you sure we're
in the right place?
- We are if this map is right.
- [Crow] Wait, this is
off a Libbyland dinner.
- What's this say, my
Greek's not very good.
- [Tom] It says,
"How do you keep
a Delta Knight busy for hours?
Turn over."
- Beneath the shape of a fist,
from the house of the one,
treasures are given.
- [Crow] Da da da
da da da da bliven.
- From father to son.
- Great, another mystery.
House of one, what's the one?
- Other than the first
words of each sentence,
the only words that are
capitalized are House and One.
- [Mike] That kind of
shirt never caught on.
- I'm the one.
- Your house. Does your
family have a house?
- [Tom] Well, a trailer.
- In Kent, it's
called Sandstone Hill.
Beneath the shape of a fist.
A sandstone rock or boulder
that looks like a fist
- Right there.
- [Crow] This is
my fist, you idiot.
- I think we can pry
it open with a stick.
- [Tom] I'm not seeing a fist.
I saw the movie "F.I.S.T".
- [Mike] A giant ground crow.
- [Crow] The first garage
door openers were cumbersome.
- Harder.
- [Tom] More
drawn-out and boring.
- Push!
- [Mike] Timothy? Where
on earth did you go?
- [Crow] Man, my eyes
have already evolved away.
♪ Have you seen my
wife, Mr. Jones ♪
- [Mike] Archimedes kept
all his Playboys in here.
- [Crow] Dragon poop, watch it.
- [Tom] Check it out,
rock looks like LBJ.
- [Crow] He's
invented bocce rock.
- [Mike] Medieval wow.
- The red book?
- [Crow] McCall's,
Good Housekeeping.
- How did you know?
- I just felt it.
- Keep feeling.
- [Tom] Hey, he who felt
it dealt it, you know.
- [Mike] Why is he
dressed like a milkmaid?
- [Crow] Hey, he's
a Puss in Boots.
- [Tom] Leonardo
da wet pants here.
- [Mike] You know what,
it's about three feet deep
and cushioned on the
bottom, you're fine.
- [Tom] I'm here for the
Bullwinkle fan club meeting.
- [Crow] Man, I'm hot.
I have got to get
a summer costume.
- [Mike] Here, rinse
that out for me.
- Men.
- [Tom] You too, Roy.
- Follow me through
the gateway to destiny.
- [Crow] But first let's check
out this crummy mine here.
(metal clanging)
- [Vultare] Mind your head.
- [Tom] That was supposed
to make us sad, right?
- [Mike] Hey Gollum,
how's it goin' man?
- [Leonardo] Try them both.
- [Crow] I think you'll
like the harvest cheddar.
- I think one is the right way
and one leads to disaster.
- [Tom] That's okay,
'cause I'm always
flirtin' with disaster.
- [Mike] Yep,
gateway to destiny.
- [Leonardo] Does the
book say anything?
"The Right Way" must say
which is the right way.
- That's it
- [Mike] Oh no,
wait, no it isn't.
- When in doubt,
choose the right way.
Let's go.
- Wait.
- [Tom] Let me get my purse.
- [Mike] Aaaaah god,
I'm dying, aaah.
- Leonardo?
Are you all right? Leonardo!
- [Mike] I'm feeling a tingle.
- Come along, men.
Destiny, remember?
- [Tom] Uh, moo, sir.
- [Mike] It's a Blind
Faith album cover.
- [Crow] Kinky.
- Man can fly.
- [Mike] So da Vinci was a moron
who stole all his ideas.
- [Tom] (dopey
laughing) It's a thing.
- The Calgon crystals.
- [Crow] I call they're mine.
- [Mike] And it flaps, see?
- [Tom] I guess Archimedes
never thought of
inventing the feather duster.
- [Crow] An early "Hi and Lois."
- There's only one
way to find out.
- [Mike] Ah, hook 'em
horns, sir, by the way.
- [Tom] I think
it's an Ace Award.
- It's capable of producing
a very powerful beam of light.
- Right, Archimedes used
intense rays of light
to fight the Romans.
Is this what he used?
- I don't think so.
This is fueled out of
the fabric of space.
- Fabric of space,
what does that mean?
- [Crow] Tencel.
- I don't know.
Sounds awesome to me.
- [Mike] Oh, my
underwear's tightening up.
- It's beautiful.
- [Tom] The magic
cyst of Archimedes!
- [Crow] Well, Mmm bop.
- Good afternoon.
- [Mike] Caw.
- [Tom] I'll get this
one, Ray, 'scuse me.
- [Crow] These Delta
Knights are taken captive
like three times a day,
it's not a good record.
- [Mike] Not at all.
We took some stuff, sir.
- At last.
- [Tom] i guard this
old futon with my life.
- So good of you
to lead the way.
- [Crow] Did you
feel the sarcasm
because that's how I meant it.
- [Mike] I was gonna say
something else. Ah, never mind.
(eerie whooshing)
- [Tom] Archimedes
wasn't that brilliant,
he was trying to design a pen.
- [Crow] Moo!
- Oh, be quiet.
- [Mike] It's a giant
mitten and it's after me!
[Tom] My turn!
- Leonardo, look.
Come on.
- What a curious device.
(instrumental theme music)
- [Tom] Ricochet Rabbit!
- They're gone.
Where is everybody?
- [Crow] I was gonna do
karaoke on this thing.
- Oh it doesn't matter,
they're only boys.
Everything here is mine.
- [Mike] Archimedes'
blow comb, everything!
- I have the power.
- [Tom] I have this thing.
- I shall rule the world.
- [Crow] I shall
enact zoning laws.
- [Mike] I gotta call Columbine
and tell her I'll
be late for lunch.
- Leonardo!
- [Tom] Leonardo da
Completely Ineffectual-ee.
- [Mike] What the-
Does everyone have canola
oil on their fingers?
- [Tom] That makes
my lips beefy.
- [Mike] I guess that yarn
mail doesn't work very good.
- [Crow] Spent from
battle, they lie
draped in each other's arms.
- [Mike] I want
his poet's shirt.
- [Tom] Enjoy much
scientific pleasure
with magnificent operation.
- [Crow] Ah, now it's
gonna be a space-time thing
and Worf's gonna pop out.
- [Tom] Tee pities the
fool who gets in his way.
(Tom imitates cat yowling)
- It's mine.
- [Tom] And the bank's.
- All mine.
- [Crow] Is the take broken?
Keep going? Yes or no.
- [Mike] Oh, it's an
Archimedes knockoff.
- [Tom] Mmm booop.
- [Mike] His body will
shield me from the blast.
(groaning)
- [Tom] Mother.
- [Mike] You want
to take a broomstick
and knock me off
of here, please?
- [Tom] Ugh, varicose veins.
(explosion)
- [Crow] Oh yeah,
fire in the hole.
- [Mike] So guys, should we be
feeling anything at this point?
- [Tom] You can go ahead and
feel something, I'm not gonna.
- [Mike] Oh, okay.
- [Crow] Oh man, is it
the Renaissance already?
- You're alive.
- You tried to kill me.
- [Mike] Ah, go paint
an enigmatic woman.
- You tried to kill me.
- [Tom] I want to see if
these are Fruit of the Loom.
- It didn't even puncture you.
- So why don't you try again?
- Look out!
- [Crow] Whoa, that
just popped out of me.
- And you didn't
think you needed me.
- Thena!
- [Mike] Breasts!
- You came!
- The storehouse.
- [Thena] I knew I had to come.
- [Tom] Why'd he
say "stoolhouse?"
- What happened to you?
- He tried to kill me.
- [Crow] Giant dink.
- I had to blow it up.
- [Tom] I'm kind
of a psycho kid.
- Why?
- Mankind isn't ready. Not yet.
- Think of all the
good it could do.
- Think of all the evil.
How many more
Vultares are there?
- But in the hands
of the order...
- I can't unleash that power
into a childlike world.
- You can't unleash it?
Who gave you the
right to decide?
- Archimedes, in his prophecy.
- That's ancient
history, this is now.
- But he was right
about so many things.
- [Mike] What are you
guys talking about?
- His inventions
were from his genius.
- And from Atlantis.
- [Tee] And what
happened to Atlantis?
- [Crow] I don't know. Shut up.
- Do we want another Atlantis?
Remember what the
Delta stands for.
Wisdom, composed of knowledge
judgment and compassion.
- [Tom] and hockey
hair under fey hats.
- I'm sorry, Leonardo.
The storehouse must remain lost.
- [Mike] That
night, Leo spiraled
into a spaghetti
and Chianti haze.
- [Crow] Anyone need
a skill saw blade?
- He's right, you know.
- [Tom] "He's right, you know."
- [Mike] I gotta say,
grazing in the grass
is a gas, baby could you dig it?
- [Crow] I must invent the
cold shower immediately.
- [Tom] She left a list
of why she hates me.
- [Narrator] Although
Leonardo burned the map
to the lost storehouse,
his thoughts
would always be inspired by
the wonders it contained.
- [Mike] And?
- [Crow] Is that it? Or...
- [Narrator] And so
the bonds of friendship
between the beautiful
princess and the two
young Delta Knights
denied the forces of evil
access to the ultimate
power, at least for a time.
- [Tom] Hey look, it's Pearl!
(excited chattering)
- [Pearl] Pipe down.
So now you wouldn't expect
those kinds of
losses, now would you?
- [Man] No, no, that's
a little unusual.
But still, it could be
a luminance problem,
or something we
call a UP leakage,
which can happen with
some of your older films.
- [Pearl] Now see,
that's what I thought
but this one was a
fairly recent film.
- [Man] Ah, that is unusual.
Why don't we just
take some readings?
- [Mike] Um, excuse me.
- [Man] Won't be a minute.
- [Mike] Pearl?
- [Pearl] Oh right,
Mike, this is
Fred Eggleston from Facilitech.
- [Man] Call me Eggs.
- [Mike] Oh, hi.
- [Bots] Hi, Eggs.
- Howdy.
- [Pearl] We're just
trying to figure out
why we're not getting
the kind of pain levels
we need from these movies.
- [Eggs] Why don't you just
have a seat there, son.
We'll be done
before you know it.
- [Mike] Oh, okay
well, thanks Eggs.
- [Crow] Thanks, Eggs.
- Thanks.
- [Eggs] Pearl,
why don't you grab
the end of this tape
measure here, hold it there.
- [Mike] Ow, watch it.
(all muttering)
- [Eggs] Well, why don't
we just snap a chalk line
so we know where
we're starting from.
Pearl, if you could
hold that there.
All right, hold it tight.
- Ow!
- Ah, geez.
(all muttering)
- [Pearl] Well, Mr.
Eggleston, now what?
- [Eggs] Well, you know,
I was just thinking,
maybe you're getting
some pain linkage
around the edges of your
viewing screen here.
Have you replaced
the weatherstripping
since you bought this rig?
- [Pearl] No, no, no I haven't.
Was I supposed to?
- [Eggs] Well, most
of our customers
with pain motivated subjects
in a theater-type environment
replace their weatherstripping
every eight to ten years.
If this is old, some
of your pain could be
escaping out the sides and
that could be your problem.
- [Mike] Excuse me,
do we need to be here?
- [Pearl] You shut up, I am
talking to Mr. Eggleston.
- [eggs[ Eggs, please.
- [Pearl] Certainly, Eggs.
- [Eggs] I'm just gonna
run a bead of caulk here
along the edge here and
take some more readings.
- [Mike] you know
what, you guys,
I'm thinking about having
a porchetta for dinner.
- [Pearl] Will you
please be quiet
so that Eggs can
run a bead of caulk?
- [Mike] Sorry.
- [Eggs] Well, there you go.
Let's see what kind of
readings we get here.
Hmm, yeah.
That helped a little
but it's still
not what we're looking for.
I hate to say this, ma'am.
- [Pearl] What, what?
- [Eggs] Well, you
might want to consider
a larger viewing
area, which would mean
replacing this
support wall over here
and raising the whole
ceiling up 24 inches or so.
- [Pearl] Oh, wow. How
much would that cost me?
- [Eggs] Oh, rough
estimate, I'd say 48 large.
- [Pearl] 48 large,
are you kidding me?
- [Tom] Still, it seems
like money well spent Pearl.
- [Crow] Yeah, pay the man now,
Pearl, or pay him later.
- [Mike] Yeah, you know,
like they always say,
Pearl, you can't make
your subject suffer
unless you spend a little
money to enlarge the theater.
- [Pearl] Oh yeah?
I'll show you pain,
and at a bargain too.
(whacking)
- Ow!
(all mumbling)
- [Eggs] That'll work too.
- [Pearl] Come along, Eggs.
- Yes ma'am.
- [Crow] Pearl, don't go!
(bots crying)
- [Mike] Did that just happen?
- [Tom] She hit me,
that means she loves me.
(mechanical rumbling)
(doors closing)
(bots crying)
- You're not Pearl.
- Oh hi, not Pearl.
I mean, Mike.
You want to look at my
Pearl scrapbook with me?
- No, no thanks, you know,
I see Pearl enough
in person, thank you.
- You take that back,
you big not Pearl!
- Hey, you know, you
guys need to talk.
It seems like you may
be having some feelings
about Pearl not
being here anymore.
- We just miss her, Mike.
- You know, she
gave us a mint once.
- A mint that had been at
the bottom of her purse
for a couple of
years, and there was
part of a tissue on it.
- And a hair!
(bots crying)
- Well, I mean, it's
great that you guys
have these wonderful
memories to keep you going.
- Thank you.
Oh, she's calling!
- Calling for me!
(bots chattering excitedly)
Pearl, Pearl?
- Oh mama.
Hey kid, you gonna finish those?
Lemme give you a
hand there, huh?
- Oh hi, Nelcreep.
Oh, hi Bony Gold Creep
and Porcine Red Creep.
Hey, get a load of
this, the Delta Knights
reserved this place for their
annual pancake breakfast
long before we even moved in.
- Would somebody
please pass the syrup!
- More cake of pan, Pearl?
- Oh yeah, lay that on me there.
Good, good, keep them comin'
and we need more
syrup over here.
- Well what do you know,
another successful
pancake breakfast.
thanks for your
help, Bobo, Pearl.
- Yeah yeah yeah yeah.
Didn't you guys used
to roam the countryside
defending the weak or
some crap like that?
- I think there's something
about that in the bylaws.
Isn't that right, Doug?
- You got that right, Frank.
- Yeah, we pretty much got it
distilled down to just
pancake breakfasts now.
In fact, everyone,
I'd like to announce
that thanks to this year's
successful pancake breakfast,
we've raised enough funds for
next year's pancake breakfast!
(cheering)
- Huzzah! Huzzah!
- And in celebration,
hard candy for everyone!
- No!
(pained yelling)
(grand stately theme music)
- Good.
- I'm coming!